Donald Hyde and Mary Hyde Eccles Autograph Collection (MS Hyde 10): Guide.
Donald Hyde and Mary Hyde Eccles Autograph Collection,
- Gwatkin, Harriet. Autograph letter, Stoke House [London?] to James Northcote, [1828] Dec. 29., (275); 1s.
  Sends an original Samuel Johnson letter (not included).
- Gwatkin, Mrs. (Theophila), d. 1843. Autograph letter, signed, Stoke House [London?] to James Northcote, 1828 Dec. 22., (276); 1s.
  Sends a turkey. On verso, two autograph letter drafts, signed, by Northcote, Argyll Place [London] 1829 Jan. 1, to Theophila Gwatkin, and to Harriet Gwatkin, thanking them for their gifts.
- Haddington, Charles Hamilton, Earl of, 1753-1828. Autograph letter, signed, Tynninghame by Dunbar [East Lothian, Scotland] to John Spottiswoode, 1810 Feb. 27., (277); 1s.
  Concerning an estate.
- [Haddington, Thomas Hamilton, Earl of, 1721-1794]? (then Lord Binning). Autograph note, Ha[milton?] [Scotland?] to James Boswell, 1791 Mar. 3., (278); 1s.
  Thanks for Letter to the People of Scotland.
- Haden, Francis Seymour, Sir, 1818-1910. Autograph letter, signed, Woodcote Manor, Alresford [Hampshire, England] to W. G. (William George) Rawlinson, 1905 July 14., (279); 1s.
  Concerning the art of J. M. W. (Joseph Mallord William) Turner.
- Hales, Stephen, 1677-1761. A short account of easie methods to refresh the foul air in hospitals, goals [gaols], barracks, and other places that are crowded with many men: autograph manuscript, [no place] [not before 1743], (280); 1s.
  An essay on ventilation. Describes medical care at the Battle of Dettingen in 1743, and French prisoners then being held at Winchester (England).
- Hall, Robert, 1764-1831. Autograph letter, signed, [Bristol, England] to James Sherman (1796-1862), [1827] May 12., (281); 1s.
  Travel plans.
- Hall, Robert, 1764-1831. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Mrs. Wilson, [1828?] Friday., (282); 1s.
  Thanks for a three-volume set of Matthew Henry's Exposition of the Old and New Testament.
- Hallam, Henry, 1777-1859. Autograph letter, signed, 24 Wilton Crescent [London] to unidentified recipient, 1846 Jan. 20., (283); 1s.
  Declines to sit for portrait.
- Hamilton, Archibald, d. 1792. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to J. (John) Nourse, 1778 July 23., (284); 1s.
  Concerning the publication of Remarks on Mr. Forster's Account of Captain Cook's Last Voyage by William Wales.
- Hamilton, Archibald, d. 1792. Books printed by Mr. Hamilton: manuscript, [no place] [1779?], (285); 1s.
  Lists printing date, number printed, title, size, number of sheets, and reams used, for more than eighty books printed from 1767 to 1779.
- Hamilton, Gavin, 1703-1767. Autograph letter, signed, Edinburgh (Scotland), to William Strahan, 1759 June 16., (286); 1s.
  Concerning an apprentice and the death of Strahan's sister.
- Hamilton, William Gerard, 1729-1796. Autograph letter, signed, Hampton Court [London?] to John Almon, [1775 Sept.?] Saturday., (287); 1s.
  Travel plans. On verso, manuscript notes in an unknown hand concerning William Pitt, Earl of Chatham.
- Hamilton, William Gerard, 1729-1796. Autograph letter, signed, Upper Brook Street [London] to unidentified recipient, [17--] Nov. 19., (288); 1s.
  Concerning a political compromise.
- Hanway, Jonas, 1712-1786. 2 autograph letters, signed, Strand [London] to John Montagu, 4th Earl of Sandwich, 1762 Feb., (289); 2s.
  Seeking a position.
- Harcourt, William Harcourt, Earl, 1743-1830. Cover: autograph document, signed, Sidmouth (England), to Lady Elliot Duke, 1823 Dec. 8., (289a); 1s.
  Cover panel of a letter, franked by Harcourt.
- Harcourt, Simon Harcourt, Earl, 1714-1777. Autograph letter, signed, D[ublin] Castle [Dublin, Ireland] to Henry Flood, 1775 Oct. 23., (290); 1s.
  Reports that the king's letter has arrived.
- Harden, [John William, b. ca. 1810?] Requisition of Mr. Rudall; observations of Mr. Harden in reply: autograph manuscript, [no place] 1844 July 10., (291); 1s.
  Description of the properties in the Brynbella estate near Denbigh, Wales formerly owned by Hester Lynch Piozzi. Written in response to a tithe official named Mr. Rudall. Harden was likely the son-in-law of estate owner Sir John Salusbury Piozzi Salusbury.
- Hardinge, Henry Hardinge, Viscount, 1785-1856. Autograph letter, signed, South Park [Kent, England] to Mr. Reniger, 1850 June 1., (292); 1s.
  Ordering sherry.
- Hardinge, Henry Hardinge, Viscount, 1785-1856. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Mr. Walter, [18--] Friday., (293); 1s.
  Arranging a visit.
- Hardwicke, Philip Yorke, Earl of, 1720-1790. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Edward Leeds, 1785 Mar. 22., (294); 1s.
  Concerning politics.
- Hargrave, Francis, 1741?-1821. Autograph letter, signed, Boswell Court [London] to Thomas Astle, 1786 Oct. 10., (295); 1s.
  Concerning efforts to identify the author of a manuscript relating to the Tower of London.
- Hargrave, Francis, 1741?-1821. Receipt: autograph document, signed, [no place] 1799 Jan. 19., (296); 1s.
  Receipt to George Robinson Co. for copyright to his Juridical Arguments and Collections.
- Hastings, Warren, 1732-1818. Autograph letter, signed, Niaseme [?] [India] to Sir Robert Chambers, 1782 Sept. 26., (297); 1s.
  Thanks for a parcel of medicinal roots.
- Hawkesworth, John, 1715?-1773. Autograph letter, signed, London, to Rev. Currey of Wombwell Hall, Kent (England), 1765 Nov. 28., (298); 1s.
  Planning a visit to Wombwell Hall.
- Hawkesworth, John, 1715?-1773. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [Lockyer?] Davis, 1766 Mar. 14., (299); 1s.
  Concerning the publication of Hawkesworth's edition of Letters Written by the Late Jonathan Swift.
- Hawkesworth, John, 1715?-1773. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [Mr. Deane] 1759 Apr. 20., (300); 1s.
  Comments on the work of Richard Price.
- Hawkesworth, John, 1715?-1773. Autograph letter, signed, Clements Inn [London] to James Dodsley, 1768 Feb. 25., (301); 1s.
  Concerning a meeting with [Peter?] Muilman.
- Hawkesworth, John, 1715?-1773. Autograph letter, signed, Bromley, Kent [England] to Fulke Greville, 1756 Mar. 14., (302); 1s.
  Discusses David Garrick and Samuel Johnson. Encloses a letter from Johnson to Hawkesworth.
  George Birkbeck Hill, ed., Letters of Samuel Johnson, LL.D. (Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1892) I, 60-61 (in part). The Johnson letter originally enclosed with this one is also published in Hill. The original is in MS Hyde 1, item (43).
- Hawkesworth, John, 1715?-1773. Autograph letter, signed, 6 Plumbtree Court [London] to [Joshua?] Parry, 1742 Nov. 24., (303); 2s.
  Social letter, commenting on Alexander Pope's Dunciad. With cover.
  Partial transcript in Adam, 121.
- Hawkesworth, John, 1715?-1773. Autograph letter, signed, Bromley, Kent [England] to unidentified recipient, 1763 June 13., (304); 1s.
  Criticizes the recent work of English geography published by the recipient.
- Hawkesworth, John, 1715?-1773. In sleep's serene oblivion laid: manuscript, [no place] 1773 [Oct.], (305); 1s.
  Poem, dictated to amanuensis Mary Brown Hawkesworth, his wife.
- Hawkesworth, Mary Brown, d. 1796. Autograph letter, signed, Bromley [Kent, England] to Eva Maria Garrick, 1773 June 20., (306); 2s.
  Concerning a misunderstanding between David Garrick and John Hawkesworth. With cover.
  Related correspondence can be found in the David Garrick Papers, MS Hyde 6, item (8).
- Hawkins, John, Sir, 1719-1789. The life of Samuel Johnson, LL.D.: manuscript, 1786., (307); 1s.
  Title page text only.
  The handwriting does not appear to be that of Hawkins.
- Haydon, Benjamin Robert, 1786-1846. Autograph letter, signed, 99 Piccadilly, Manchester (England), to unidentified recipient, 1837 June 3., (308); 1s.
  Responding to an autograph request. Illustrated with a pen and ink drawing of a foot. With intact seal.
- Hayes, Samuel, 1749-ca. 1795. Autograph letter, signed, 322 Oxford Street [London?] to James Lackington, 1790 Jan. 28., (309); 1s.
  Concerning a new edition of Samuel Johnson's Lives of the English Poets.
- Hayley, William, 1745-1820. Autograph letter draft, [no place] to Mr. Miles, 1814 Apr. 28., (310); 1s.
  Concerning an edition of William Cowper's poems to be edited by John Johnson (1769-1833).
- Heath, James, 1757-1834. Ticket: document, signed, London, [1833?] Feb. 26, Monday., (311); 1s.
  Signature on an engraved ticket to a Royal Academy lecture. Signed on verso by J. Glover.
- Hector, Edmund, 1708-1794. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to his great-nephew Walter C[arles] Hopper, [ca. 1785-1794] Aug. 19., (312); 1s.
- Hector, Edmund, 1708-1794. Autograph letter draft, [no place] to Samuel Johnson, [1784 Nov. or Dec.], (313); 3s.
  Includes a manuscript transcript of Hector's memorandum on his boyhood memories of Johnson, sent at Johnson's request. According to a later letter from Hector to James Boswell dated 1785 Feb. 1, Johnson "only receiv'd them a few days before his death." With typescript transcript.
  This copy was later published by Sir John Hawkins in his Life of Samuel Johnson, LL.D. (London: 1787), 7-8. A variant copy of the memorandum was published in Marshall Waingrow, ed., The Correspondence and Other Papers of James Boswell Relating to the Making of the Life of Johnson (New York: McGraw-Hill, [1969?]) 49-51.
- Hely-Hutchinson, John, 1724-1794. Autograph letter, signed, Palmerston House [Dublin, Ireland] to [Edmund Burke] 1790 Dec. 13., (314); 1s.
  Comments on Burke's Reflections on the Revolution in France, and speculates what Samuel Johnson's reaction would have been.
- Henley, William Ernest, 1849-1903. Autograph letter, signed, 11 Howard Place, Edinburgh (Scotland), to H. B. Marriott (Henry Brereton Marriott) Watson, 1891 Apr. 24., (315); 1s.
  Mentions J. M. (James Matthew) Barrie.
- Henry, Robert, 1718-1790. Autograph letter, signed, Edinburgh (Scotland), to William Strahan, 1781 Apr. 21., (316); 1s.
  Discusses the public reception of his The History of Great Britain.
- Herschel, Margaret, Lady, 1810-1884?. Autograph letter, signed, Collingwood [Kent, England] to her husband Sir John F. W. (John Frederick William) Herschel, [1854 Sept.?] 23, Tuesday., (317); 1s.
  Family news. Acquired with a diary by Lady Herschel dated 1832-1846, MS Hyde 21.
- Hertford, Francis Seymour Conway, Marquess of, 1719-1794. Autograph letter, signed, Paris, to [George] Grenville, 1764 Jan. 22., (318); 1s.
  Seeking a position for Benjamin Couch.
- Hertford, Francis Seymour Conway, Marquess of, 1719-1794. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, 1780 July 25., (319); 1s.
  Concerning Willoughby Bertie, Earl of Abingdon, and the parliamentary elections.
- Hervey, [naval officer] Autograph letter, signed, Portsmouth (England), to "the Principal Officers of the Ordnance," 1781 May 25., (320); 1s.
  Concerning his transfer from HMS Daphne to HMS Recovery.
- Hervey, James, 1714-1758. Autograph letter, signed, Weston [Northamptonshire, England] to his sister [unidentified] 1752 Oct. 16., (321); 1s.
  Describing a hunt.
- Hesketh, Harriet, Lady, 1733-1807. Autograph letter, signed, Tonbridge (England), to unidentified recipient, 1776 Aug. 25., (322); 1s.
  Concerning the sale of property.
- Hett, John. Proposed partnership of sundry booksellers: autograph document, signed, Chancery Lane [London] 1776 June 16., (323); 1s.
  Partnership agreement, drafted in an unknown hand, attested with a legal opinion by Hett, and signed by more than sixty booksellers, including William Strahan,; T. (Thomas) Cadell,; Charles Rivington,; George Robinson, and James Dodsley.
- Hill, George Birkbeck Norman, 1835-1903. Autograph letter, signed, 4 Lulworth Road, Southport [Lancashire, England] to Marseille M. (Marseille Middleton) Holloway, 1881 Aug. 19., (324); 1s.
  Discusses the character of Charles George Gordon.
- Hill, George Birkbeck Norman, 1835-1903. 2 autograph letters, signed, 1 Nassington Road, Hampstead (London), to [Edward J.] Leveson, 1887-1889., (325); 2s.
  Concerning the Johnson Club (London, England).
- Hill, George Birkbeck Norman, 1835-1903. Autograph letter, signed, Maison Martin, Baugy sur Clarens, Vaud, Switzerland, to unidentified recipient, 1894 Dec. 20., (326); 1s.
  Comments on Harvard University, and on the relative interest in Samuel Johnson in England and the United States.
- Hill, George Birkbeck Norman, 1835-1903. Autograph letter, signed, Villa Venusta, Alassio (Italy), to unidentified recipient, 1897 Jan. 22., (327); 1s.
  Comments on the sales of his Samuel Johnson works.
- Hill, George Birkbeck Norman, 1835-1903. Ah me! I love a deep-sunk lane: autograph manuscript, Hill Brow, Streatham [London] 1881 Oct. 10., (328); 1s.
  Poem apparently written for Marseille M. (Marseille Middleton) Holloway and his wife Anna Holloway.
- Hill, George Birkbeck Norman, 1835-1903. Johnson's letter to John Levett: autograph manuscripts, signed, [no place] 1897-1901., (329); 4s.
  Four drafts of Hill's note on a letter from Samuel Johnson to John Levett of 1752 Mar. 17, apparently written for a possible second edition of Letters of Samuel Johnson, LL.D.
- Hill, George Birkbeck Norman, 1835-1903. Note on Dr. Johnson's letter to Mr. Strahan dated Nov. 30 1774: autograph document, signed, 8 Holywell Street, Oxford (England), 1886 Aug. 15., (330); 1s.
  Draft of Hill's note concerning a letter from Samuel Johnson to William Strahan.
  The final version of Hill's note appears in his Letters of Samuel Johnson, LL.D. (Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1892) I, 300-301.
- Hill, George Birkbeck Norman, 1835-1903. On my friend M.M.H.: autograph manuscript, signed, The Poplars, Burghfield [Berkshire, England] 1878 Sept., (331); 1s.
  Poem for Marseille M. (Marseille Middleton) Holloway. On verso, Answer to the Hills, autograph manuscript poem, signed, by Anna Holloway, Hill Brow [Surrey, England]
- Hill, Joseph, 1733-1811. Autograph letter, signed, Wargrave near Maidenhead (England), to unidentified recipient, 1802 Aug. 24., (332); 1s.
  Unable to help with request.
- Hill, Marcus, d. 1751. Autograph letter, signed, Goose Green [Hampshire, England] to John Huggins, 1739 Dec. 20., (333); 1s.
  Has stocked Heath House Park with deer.
- Hill, Peter. Autograph letter, signed, Edinburgh (Scotland), to Vernor, Hood and Sharpe, 1808 Mar. 22., (334); 1s.
  Concerning publication of James Playfair's A System of Geography.
- Hoadly, John, 1711-1776. Autograph letter, signed, Old Alresford [Hampshire, England] to Mr. Burn, 1768 Aug. 25., (335); 1s.
  Unable to recommend Burn to Jonathan Shipley, Bishop of Llandaff.
- Hoadly, John, 1711-1776. 2 autograph letters, signed, to [Robert Dodsley?] 1757., (336); 2s.
  The 1757 Nov. 1 letter concerns his verses accompanying William Hogarth's Rake's Progress, and is trimmed with some loss of text. The 1758 Dec. 11 letter sends his poems to be anthologized.
- Hobbes, Thomas, 1588-1679. Manuscript letter, [no place] to William Cavendish, Duke of Newcastle, 1640 May 9., (337); 1s.
  Discusses the difference between mathematical and dogmatic knowledge. Manuscript transcript, in an unknown hand.
  Reader reports that this is the dedicatory epistle taken from a scribal copy of Hobbes's treatise The Elements of Law, and that the copy from which it was taken is now at Chatsworth House, Bakewell, Derbyshire: MS Hobbes A.2.A [note added 2007 September 24].
  Partial transcript in Adam, 128-129.
- Hoby, Edward, Sir, 1560-1617. Certificates: manuscript documents, [no place] 1594., (338); 3s.
  Two certificates concerning rents due from Hoby to Brasenose College (University of Oxford), both signed by Thomas Singleton and William Townley. With a related autograph letter, signed, from Alexander Nowell to the Privy Council of England and Wales, 1593 Feb. 12.
- Hogarth, William, 1697-1764. Receipt: document, signed, [no place] 1762 Oct. 30., (339); 1s.
  Order to pay Hogarth, signed by James Waldegrave, Earl Waldegrave; and by Henry Fiennes Pelham-Clinton, Duke of Newcastle (then Earl of Lincoln). On verso, receipt signed by Hogarth and witness Edward Crocker.
- Hogg, James, 1770-1835. Autograph letter, signed, Edinburgh (Scotland), to Mrs. Eliza [Izet?] of Kinnaird (Perthshire, Scotland), 1814 Jan. 22., (340); 1s.
  Discusses his current literary work.
- Holland, Henry Richard Vassall, Baron, 1773-1840. 2 autograph letters, signed, Holland House [Kensington, London] to Charles Stuart, Baron Stuart de Rothesay, 1829., (341); 2s.
  Concerning a daughter of the late Sackville Tufton, Earl of Thanet.
- Holland, Henry Richard Vassall, Baron, 1773-1840. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [1837?] May 3., (342); 1s.
  Concerning a political dispute between Sir Francis Burdett and John Temple Leader.
- Hollis, Joseph-Samuel, b. ca. 1763. Autograph letter, signed, Romsey, Hampshire (England), to W. Grave, bookseller of the Strand, London, 1798 Apr. 20., (343); 1s.
  Concerning a French translation of Samuel Johnson's Rasselas by the comte de Fouchecour.
- Home, John, 1722-1808. Douglas, a tragedy: autograph manuscript, [no place] [1757?], (344); 1s.
  One leaf from Home's manuscript draft, corresponding with page 39 of the 1757 first edition.
- Hook, Theodore Edward, 1788-1841. Hester Lynch Piozzi: manuscript transcript, [1833?], (344a); 1s.
  Transcript in an unknown hand of a marginal note written by Hook in an 1833 volume, concerning the relationship between Hester Lynch Piozzi and William Augustus Conway.
  With a related note in a different unidentified hand below.
- Hoole, John, 1727-1803. 3 autograph letters, signed, Great Queen Street [London] to William Bowles, 1784 Dec. 11 to 14., (345); 3s.
  Describing the final days of Samuel Johnson.
- Horne, George, 1730-1792. Letter, signed, [no place] to Mrs. Green, 1791 Dec. 27., (346); 1s.
  Trimmed address panel signed as Bishop of Norwich, on verso of a letter fragment. The address and letter fragment are in different hands.
- Horne, George, 1730-1792. Autograph letter, Magdalen College [Oxford, England] to unidentified recipient, 1788 Mar. 18., (347); 1s.
  Discusses Hester Lynch Piozzi's Letters to and from the Late Samuel Johnson, as well as James Boswell's anticipated biography of Samuel Johnson. Also discusses Thomas Harmer's Observations on Divers Passages of Scripture. The letter has been trimmed with some loss of text.
- Houghton, Richard Monckton Milnes, Baron, 1809-1885. Autograph letter, signed, 26 Pall Mall [London] to Mr. Booth, [1847 May] 14., (348); 1s.
  Wants to arrange an exchange of publications with Booth's friend.
- Houghton, Richard Monckton Milnes, Baron, 1809-1885. Autograph letter, signed, 27 Berkeley Square [London] to Mr. Schlesinger, [not before 1863] July 22., (349); 1s.
  Forwards a note.
- Houston, Hugh. Invoice: document, signed, Demerara, 1796 May 19., (350); 1s.
  Invoice from merchants Hugh McCalmon Co. to Valentine Jones, Commissary General for supplies. Attested by merchants Hugh Houston and R. Murray, and certified by A. Dalzell. Receipted on verso by McCalmon.
- Howard, George, Sir, 1718-1796. Autograph letter, signed, Chelsea College [London] to Sir John Dick, 1785 May 29., (351); 1s.
  Thanks for introduction to James Boswell and for the copy of Boswell's Letter to the People of Scotland on the Alarming Attempt to Infringe the Articles of the Union.
- Hume, Abraham, Sir, 1749-1838. Autograph letter, signed, Hill Street [London] to [Mr. Peregaux?] 1787 Dec. 13., (352); 1s.
  Ordering a harp.
- Hume, David, 1711-1776. Bond: autograph document, signed, St. Andrews Square, Edinburgh (Scotland), 1776 July 6., (353); 1s.
  Bond to his servant Margaret Irwin. Paper loss at the folds with some loss of text.
- Hunter, John. Receipt: autograph document, signed, [Lichfield, England] 1705 Dec. 8., (354); 1s.
  Receipts signed by John Hunter and Humphrey Hawkins to the trustees of the Lichfield Conduit Lands Trust.
- Hunter, John, 1728-1793. Autograph letter, signed, Belleisle [Belle-Ile-en-Mer, France] to his brother William Hunter (1718-1783), 1762 Mar. 23., (355); 1s.
  Describes his duties as a military surgeon.
- Hunter, John, 1728-1793. Receipt: document, signed, London, 1773 Apr. 12., (356); 1s.
  Receipt to Joseph Johnson (1738-1809) for copyright to A Treatise on the Natural History of the Human Teeth.
- Hunter, Joseph, 1783-1861. Autograph letter, signed, Bath (England), to William Upcott, 1829 Dec. 12., (357); 1s.
  Concerning publication of the diary of Ralph Thoresby.
- Hutchinson, Francis, [1661-1739?] Order to pay: autograph document, signed, [no place] 1715 Mar. 1., (358); 1s.
  Order to pay South Sea Company stock dividends to John Humphreys on Hutchinson's behalf. Addressed to John Grigsby at South Sea House [London]
- Ireland, Samuel, d. 1800. Autograph note, 8 Norfolk Street, Strand [London] to Eva Marie Garrick, [1796] Feb. 25 and undated., (359); 2s.
  The 1795 note is an invitation to view William Shakespeare manuscripts, later discovered to have been forged by Ireland's son, William Henry Ireland. The undated note discusses the work of William Hogarth.
- Irving, Edward, 1792-1834. Autograph letter, signed, [London] to unidentified recipient, [1823?] Apr. 10 Friday., (360); 1s.
  Declines a speaking invitation. The paper bears an 1822 watermark, and the letter was apparently written soon after Irving's arrival in London in 1822.
- Irwin, Eyles, 1751?-1817. Autograph letter, signed, Madras (India), to William Hayley, 1782 Oct. 30., (361); 1s.
  Discusses Hayley's character and poetry.
- Jan II Kazimierz, King of Poland, 1609-1672. Document, signed, [no place] 1656 Apr. 20., (362); 1s.
  Concerning Hungary and Transylvania (Romania). With attached seal stamped in paper. In Latin.
- Jansenius, Cornelius, 1585-1638. Autograph letter, signed, Ypres [Ieper] (Belgium), to unidentified recipient, 1637 June 30., (363); 1s.
  In Latin. Signed as "Corn. Ep." Some text crossed out, including signature.
- Jeans, John. Autograph letter, signed, London, to Marmaduke Tunstall, 1784 July 20., (364); 1s.
  Includes a manuscript catalog of fossils collected in Scotland, and offered for sale.
- Jeffrey, Francis Jeffrey, Lord, 1773-1850. Autograph letter, signed, 24 Moray Place [Edinburgh, Scotland] to H. Lumsden, advocate, 8 King Street, Edinburgh (Scotland), [18--] 29, Tuesday., (365); 1s.
  Concerning "the Slug Road case."
- Jeffrey, Francis Jeffrey, Lord, 1773-1850. Autograph letter, signed, 24 Moray Place [Edinburgh, Scotland] to George Tawse [?] 1849 Jan. 27., (366); 1s.
  Responding to an autograph request.
- Jenyns, Soame, 1704-1787. Here lies Poor Johnson: manuscript, [no place] [between 1784-1787], (367); 1s.
  Epitaph of Samuel Johnson in unknown hand, beginning "Here lies Poor Johnson reader haveacare."
  Credited to Jenyns and published as "Epitaph on Dr. Johnson" in Alexander Chalmers, ed., The Works of the English Poets (London, 1810) XVII, 622.
- Jenyns, Soame, 1704-1787. Indenture: autograph document, signed, London, 1776 June 4., (368); 1s.
  Assignment of copyright for his A View of the Internal Evidence of the Christian Religion to James Dodsley. On verso, Jenyns's receipt to Dodsley for payment, 1777 Jan. 17.
- Jephson, Robert, 1736-1803. Autograph letter, signed, Blackrock (Ireland), to Edmond Malone, 1800 July 17., (369); 1s.
  Commenting on Malone's The Critical and Miscellaneous Prose Works of John Dryden.
- Jesse, Edward, 1780-1868. Autograph letter, signed, Windsor [Berkshire, England] to Sir William Jackson Hooker, 1843 Feb. 16., (370); 1s.
  Solicits information concerning mistletoe.
- Johnson, Joseph, 1738-1809. Agreement: document, signed, [London] 1788 Jan. 22., (371); 1s.
  Agreement with the Royal College of Physicians of London for the publication of Pharmacopoeia Collegii Regalis Medicorum Londinensis. Also signed for the college by Sir George Baker,; James Hervey (1751-1824),; George Fordyce, and David Pitcairn.